<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Emmanuel Bosquet</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Emmanuel Bosquet</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>bjokac@gmail.com (Emmanuel Bosquet)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>bjokac@gmail.com (Emmanuel Bosquet)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 18:51:20 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Unix sockets, the basics in Rust</title>
    <link>/2022/whatsaunixsocket/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 18:51:20 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/2022/whatsaunixsocket/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I found myself wondering about unix sockets while working on Sōzu, a reverse proxy written in Rust. A bunch of Sōzu issues led me to dig into Sōzu channels, which themselves make use of Metal I/O &rsquo;s implementation of unix sockets.
Here are the questions, summed up:
 what are unix sockets? how can we create them in Rust? how do we use them to stream data?  So here we go.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>My resume but it&#39;s only the gaps</title>
    <link>/2021/myresumebutitsonlythegaps/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/2021/myresumebutitsonlythegaps/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is an answer to all those recruiters asking &ldquo;How do you explain this gap in your resume?&rdquo;.
I couldn&rsquo;t stand pretending to be a healthy human being, so here is the truth.
(born 1986)
 2004 - 2005, Caen, Normandy. First year of a Physics Measurements degree. Failed spectacularly. 2007-10 - 2007-12, Stuttgart, Germany. Wandering in Germany searching for a job. 2008-10 - 2009-03, Heidelberg, Germany. Learning japanese at the university hoping to work in Japan.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Rust, ou le plaisir de coder</title>
    <link>/2021/rustouleplaisirdecoder/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/2021/rustouleplaisirdecoder/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Voici la conférence que j&rsquo;ai animée au CaenCamp en octobre 2021, où je passe en revue les bases de Rust, au compilateur très pédagogique.
  En plus de la vidéo, retrouvez :
 Les slides en ligne Le dépôt github avec tous le code présenté, et plus encore  ]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Tetris in the browser</title>
    <link>/2020/tetrisinthebrowser/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/2020/tetrisinthebrowser/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[One day I understood I could write javascript the proper way :
 object-oriented with separate files with JSdocs types as far away from the HTML as possible  AND have it work in the browser.
So I ported my dear tetris logic I had written in Rust for the terminal into the browser, using canvas.
Play it here. I&rsquo;m afraid it only works on the desktop, and it may be buggy, but hey I made a tetris, how awesome is that?]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
